把矩阵化为行阶梯形
reducing a matrix to its row echelon form
翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
♡无偿翻译，用爱发电♡
使用AI工具翻译，如有不准确的地方请在弹幕或评论区指正，谢谢！
求解由该矩阵所表示的方程组是完全相同的
is the exact same as solving the system of equations that it’s made from.
有什么问题吗？
Questions?
嗯 我们什么时候能用上这个？
Yeah, uh, when will we ever need this?
你有没有遇到过这种情况？
Has this ever happened to you?
你是否曾希望你的学生
Have you ever wished that your students would pay attention
在他们荒芜无意义的人生里 哪怕认真一次？
for once in their desolate, meaningless lives?
隆重介绍……我的世界：教育版
Introducing… Minecraft: Education Edition.
研究表明 学生通过Minecraft学习时更有动力
Studies show that students are more motivated when they learn through Minecraft.
而学生更有动力时 他们记住的信息也更多
And when students are more motivated, they hold on to more information.
Minecraft可以教授你能想到的任何科目
Minecraft can teach any subject you can think of,
让教师从讲台上的圣人 变成非凡学习之旅身边的向导
turning the teacher from a sage on the stage to a guide on the side of incredible learning.
教育版让学习更有趣、更具包容性
Education Edition makes learning more fun and inclusive.
今天就来看看吧
Check it out today.
好吧 如果教育版Minecraft这么好 那我们为什么不把它娶回家呢？
Okay, well, if educational Minecraft is so good, then why don’t we marry it?
它看起来确实能完全取代学校
It sure does seem like it could just replace school entirely,
但当你真正开始用它时……
but when you actually start using it, ehhhh…
我说这话一点也不夸张
I’m not exaggerating when I say that
教育版是微软目前开发的最烂的Minecraft版本
Education Edition is the worst Minecraft version that Microsoft currently develops.
它昂贵、不可靠、充满bugjump 还在主动传播错误信息
It’s expensive, unreliable, broken, and actively spreads incorrect information.
你知道的 全是老师们最爱的东西
Y’know, all things that teachers love.
他们几乎没更新过任何功能
They’ve barely updated any of the features
自从十年前它随基岩版一同发布以来
since it initially released with Bedrock Edition a decade ago.
下载课程的网站仍然不可用 距离被要求修复已经过去好几年了
The website where you download the lessons is still broken, years after it was asked to be fixed.
这个版本的所有决策都暴露了微软对教育的真实想法
All of the decisions in this version show what Microsoft actually thinks about education,
那就是他们想要全部好处 却连最低限度都不愿做到
which is that they want all of the benefit while doing less than the bare minimum.
而我之所以知道它有多烂 是因为
And the reason I know it’s bad is because
在这之前 我们曾经有一个好得多的教师版本
we used to have a much better version for teachers before this one.
那个版本展示了如果微软真的在乎教师 他们会怎么做
This version shows what Microsoft would do if they actually cared about the teachers,
而不只是想着从他们身上榨钱
not just wanting to extract money out of them.
它直观、易用
It’s intuitive, easy to use,
可靠到在被教育版杀死十多年后仍然能运行
and so reliable that it still works more than a decade after it was killed by Education Edition.
这个古老的、获Mojang认可的Minecraft模组简直不可思议
This old Mojang-approved Minecraft mod is incredible,
但它在教育版的冲击下基本被遗忘了
but it has basically been forgotten in the wake of Education Edition.
那么 那个版本到底是什么？
So what was this version?
它又怎么会变成现在这样？
How did it become this?
而为什么微软似乎连教育版自己都不在乎？
And why does Microsoft seem to not even care about Education Edition?
学习咨询
故事要一直追溯到Beta 1.0版本
The story goes all the way back to Beta 1.0.
下界是万圣节更新中一个全新的特性
The Nether is a brand new feature in the Halloween update,
而Minecraft整体的人气也在飞速攀升
and Minecraft as a whole is very quickly ramping up in popularity.
它变得如此受欢迎 许多老师开始注意到它
It’s getting so popular that many teachers were starting to find out about it,
大概是通过那些上课时偷偷玩它的痴迷学生
probably through their obsessed students playing it during class.
很多学校的IT部门会立刻来个360°跳杀瞬狙式封禁Minecraft
Many school IT departments would instantly 360 ladder-stall no-scope Minecraft immediately,
但一些教育工作者把这种痴迷视为机会
but some educators saw that obsession as an opportunity.
其中一位就是Santeri Koivisto
One such educator was Santeri Koivisto.
不 不是那个著名的钢管舞者 是这个书呆子大学生
No, not the famous pole dancer, okay, this nerdy college kid.
听我说完天哪
Stay with me. Jesus Christ.
他即将获得教育学学士学位
He’s about to get his bachelor’s degree in education,
他是一名代课老师
he’s a substitute teacher,
他创办了一家名为Study Consulting Group的辅导公司
he started a tutoring company called Study Consulting Group,
而且他逮着机会就狂吹自己这件事
and he’s glazing himself about it every second he can.
“暑假今天就结束了”
“The summer holiday ends today”
我的天
Oh god.
“暑假今天就结束了 我们又该去辛苦劳作了”
“The summer holiday ends today, and we get to toil once more.”
“接下来的三周将是本公司历史上最有大事发生的三周”
“The next three weeks will be the most eventful in this company’s history.”
“宣传单已经准备好了
“Advertising sheets are now ready,
很快它们就会出现在学校、市场等地的墙上 供人惊叹”
and soon they’ll be marveled at on the walls of schools, markets, and the like.”
尽管他们的Facebook主页总共只有四个赞
This is despite the fact that their Facebook page had four likes in total,
其中三个还来自他的家人
three of which were from his family members.
他们有一个我这辈子见过最烂的logo之一
They have one of the worst logos that I’ve ever seen in my entire life,
而我们只有证据证明有一批学生真的接受过辅导
and we only have proof of one set of students actually getting tutored.
于是在2010年底 他暂停下来专注于完成学位
So in late 2010, he took a break to focus on getting his degree.
他上了一门关于跨媒介教学的课
He was in a class that was about teaching across multiple mediums,
他偶然产生了在课堂上使用这款新方块游戏的想法
and he stumbled upon the idea of using this new block game in the classroom.
作为课程的一部分 他和三个朋友在附近一所小学进行了试运行
So as part of the class, he and three friends did a trial run at a small school nearby.
学生们通过它学习 这很不错
The students were learning through it, which was cool.
但真正说服Santeri的 是其他老师的反响
But what really convinced Santeri was the response from the other teachers.
他们被Minecraft迷住了
They were enamored by Minecraft,
并开始各自思考能用它做什么
and they started independently thinking about what they could do with it,
以及他们的同事能用它做什么
and what their colleagues could do with it.
这款游戏并不真正适合老师 它有bug 安装也有点麻烦
The game’s not really fit for teachers, it’s buggy and kinda hard to install.
但只要稍加修改 它就能表现得出色
But with a bit of modification, it could do super well.
哦！好主意
Oh! Uh, great idea:
如果由他来制作那个模组呢？
What if he is the one to make that mod?
一个专门为教师打造的一站式商店
A one-stop shop just for teachers.
制作自定义课程所需的一切 都可以完整地放进一个Minecraft模组里
Everything you need to make custom lessons could be fully inside of a Minecraft mod.
而且你可以让安装变得超级简单
And you could make it super easy to install
这样所有感兴趣的老师们 只需几个小时就能把它装好跑起来
so that all those interested teachers could get it up and running in, like, just a few hours.
酷！
Cool!
但是 具体要怎么做呢？
But, um, how do you do that exactly?
“安装简单”到底是什么意思？
What does “easy to install” even mean?
老师们需要这款游戏有哪些“生物特性”？
What creature features do teachers need for this game?
你要如何向一个从未玩过电子游戏的人介绍Minecraft？
How do you introduce Minecraft to somebody who’s never played a video game before?
或者……从未用过电脑的人？
Or… never used a computer before?
一堂Minecraft课到底会是什么样子？
What would a lesson in Minecraft even look like?
要回答所有这些问题 他需要去询问 比如……
To answer all those questions, he would need to ask, like…
数百名学生和老师 然后取个平均值
hundreds of students and teachers and get the average.
他到底要怎么做？
How the hell is he gonna do that?
嘿 你听说过
Hey, have you heard of
科学节
这可是全芬兰最大的小学生和老师集会
It’s only the largest convention of elementary school students and their teachers
in all of Finland.
而且就在他的学校举办！
And it’s at his school!
就在三个月后！
In three months!
那可真巧
Oh, well, that’s convenient.
Santeri和另外五个同学将在SciFest上办一个Minecraft展位
Santeri and five other classmates would run a Minecraft exhibit at SciFest.
乐高的展位一定对此相当不爽
The LEGO booth must have been pretty angry about that.
在为期四天的集会上
Over the four-day convention,
他们向一千多名学生介绍了Minecraft及其系统
they got to introduce Minecraft and its systems to over 1,000 students.
而这个数字其实还是偏低的
And that number was actually low,
因为还有一千名学生想玩
because another 1,000 students wanted to play,
但整个集会期间展位一直爆满 没能玩上
but couldn’t because they were at capacity the whole entire convention.
这让他们对如何向任何新学生介绍Minecraft有了大量见解
This gave them a ton of perspectives on how you introduce Minecraft to any new student.
如果你对游戏一无所知
If you don’t know anything about the game,
老师讲解操作、世界和机制
a teacher lecturing about the controls, world, and mechanics
是最好的入门方式
is the best way to get started.
但已经了解Minecraft的学生觉得这些无聊透顶
But students who already do know about Minecraft find those really boring.
他们更喜欢自己在网上学习
They prefer to learn for themselves on the internet.
为了解决这个问题 他们把介绍方式错开
To solve this, they staggered their introductions.
一组人看YouTube视频或浏览wiki
One group watches a YouTube video or browses the wiki,
而另一组则接受讲解
while the other is getting lectured.
然后所有人会同时进入游戏
And they would all get on the game at the same time.
学生们会被要求把名字首字母刻在地上
The students would be told to carve their initials into the ground,
或者盖一座小房子来熟悉操作
or build a small house to get them used to the controls.
只有完成所有这些之后 才能给学生一个要实现的目标
And only after all of that could they give the students a goal to achieve,
无论是构想和创造一个环境
whether it be imagining and creating an environment,
还是在社会中生活
or living in a society.
Santeri发现 Minecraft不会自动让学生投入其中
Santeri would find out that Minecraft wasn’t automatically engaging on its own.
只有当老师每一步都做对时 学生才会感兴趣
Students were only interested if the teacher did everything right.
否则 学生们真的可以直接走人 去乐高展位
If not, the students could literally just leave and go over to the LEGO booth.
老师们需要有吸引力
The teachers needed to be engaging,
而且需要很多老师
and they needed a lot of them.
他们最终确定的配比大约是每八名学生配一位老师
The ratio they landed on was about one teacher for every eight students,
而一般小学的配比是每21名学生才有一位老师
whereas the average elementary school only has one teacher for every 21 students.
我想说的是 Minecraft不是什么免费的教具
What I’m trying to say is that Minecraft is not some kind of free teaching tool.
把它摆在学生面前不是神奇的作弊码
Putting it in front of a student isn’t a magical cheat code,
你仍然得正确地使用它
you’ve still got to do it right.
而传授正确的用法 就是他做这个模组的总体目标
And relaying how to do it right would be his overall goal with this mod.
生意人
Santeri是个生意人 所以自然而然地
Santeri is a businessman, so naturally,
他想把这个小小的模组想法变成一门真正的生意
he wanted to turn this small mod idea into an actual business.
不过在当时
At the time though,
做Minecraft模组根本赚不到什么钱
there wasn’t really any money in making Minecraft mods,
尤其是这么小众的东西
especially for something this niche.
于是在3月23日
So, on March 23rd,
Santeri给Mojang发了一封邮件 详细说明了他的计划
Santeri sent an email to Mojang detailing his plans.
“我在等一封来自瑞典的邮件”
“I’m waiting for an email from Sweden.”
“如果它带来好消息 一个巨大的齿轮就将开始转动……”
“If it brings positive news, then a big wheel will start turning…”
“一个比以前更大的齿轮”
“An even bigger one than before.”
然后……
And…
他们完全无视了它
they completely ignored it.
因为……他们当然会这样？
Because… of course they did?
这家伙到底是谁啊？
Who the fuck even is this guy?
作为回应 Santeri开始在Twitter上含含糊糊地发帖
In response, Santeri started vagueposting about it on Twitter.
4月3日 为了让这件事成真做最后的努力
On April 3rd, in a final attempt to get this to work,
他跑到Notch的Twitter上开始求他
he went to Notch’s Twitter and just started pleading to him.
那条推文和Minecraft毫无关系
That tweet didn’t have anything to do with Minecraft.
但不知怎么地
But through some miracle,
在他发出这条推文三天后
three days after he posted this,
他收到了回复邮件
he got his email back.
好吧 现在我糊涂了
Okay, well now I’m confused.
要么 A 他们真的花了整整两周才想明白怎么回复这家伙……
Either, A, it genuinely took them two entire weeks to figure out how to respond to this guy…
……要么 B 这条措辞糟糕的推文不知为何引起了Notch的注意
…or two, this poorly worded tweet got Notch’s attention for some reason.
两者对我来说都难以置信
Both of them seem unbelievable to me.
但其中一种必定是事情的真相
But one of them had to be what happened,
因为不知怎么的 这个来自芬兰的普通大学生
because, somehow now, this random college student from Finland
现在正在和Mojang的首席执行官通Skype电话
is on a Skype call with the CEO of Mojang.
Santeri告诉Carl Manneh 凭借在SciFest的经验
Santeri told Carl Manneh that with the SciFest experience,
他将是制作Minecraft教育版的理想人选
he would be a prime candidate to make an educational version of Minecraft.
你知道的 如果他们想涉足这方面的话
You know, if they ever wanted to get into that or anything.
但要实现这一点 他需要他们的支持
But to do it, he would need their support.
鉴于学校是长期增长的巨大市场
Given that schools are a huge place for long-term growth,
他没花多久就答应了
it didn’t take him long to say yes.
在那之后 一切就飞速开始了
And after that, it was off to the races.
首先他雇佣了Aleksi Postari
First he hired Aleksi Postari,
一位东芬兰大学的本科生同学
a fellow undergrad at UEF.
他学的也是教育专业
He’s also in education,
但他比Santeri更懂编程
but he knows a lot more about coding than Santeri.
所以Aleksi才是真正写模组代码的人
So Aleksi would be the one actually coding the mod.
策略是：
The strategy is:
如果东西没坏 那就……
if it ain’t broke, then...
我的意思是 那就继续做你正在做的事吧
I mean, just keep on doing what you’re doing then.
它应该还是Minecraft
It should still be Minecraft,
只是加上一点教育元素
but just with a little bit of education on top.
他们就是这么起的名
And that’s how they named it.
没人想玩一个为了教育而降低难度的Minecraft版本
Nobody wants to play a dumbed-down version of Minecraft for education.
你能想象那种东西吗？
Can you even imagine such a thing?
主要的修改应该面向老师
The main modification should be for the teachers.
给他们那种“造物特性”
Give them the creature– f-feature,
管我之前怎么说呢
whatever I said earlier.
他们不需要游戏内置任何课程
They didn’t need any kind of lessons to be built into the game.
课程应该由老师为每个具体班级量身制作
They should be made for each specific class by the teacher.
不要恼人的标准化
No pesky standardization,
要个性化
but personalization.
有谁比任课老师更了解学生呢？
Who knows the students better than their own instructor?
实现这一点的最佳方式是制作一个客户端模组
The best way to allow this was to make a client-side mod.
它非常便宜
It was super cheap,
而且赋予他们很大能力 基本上可以对游戏为所欲为
and it gave them a lot of power to basically do whatever they wanted to the game.
Aleksi负责编写模组代码
Aleksi would code up the mod
而Santeri负责商业方面的事务
while Santeri was working on the business side of things.
理论上 他们俩就能撑起整个公司
And in theory, these two could just be the business,
但他们有一个小问题
but they have a small problem.
或者说……问题就在于他们太小了
Or… the problem is that they’re small.
没人知道他们是谁
Nobody knows who the heck they are.
他们公司至今的全部履历 就是在自己学校的集会上展出
Their entire company history so far is exhibiting at their own school’s convention
以及在Facebook上获得四个赞
and getting four likes on Facebook.
他们需要触达更多人
They need to reach more people,
但他们俩主要说芬兰语
but they both mainly speak Finnish,
这让他们与庞大的Minecraft受众群隔绝开来
cutting them off from the gigantic Minecraft audience
那个正在英语世界形成的受众群
that was being built in the English-speaking world.
天哪 要是有一位受欢迎的Minecraft教育者
Man, if only there was a popular Minecraft educator
母语是英语 而且他们能联系上就好了
who natively spoke English that they could get in touch with.
镜头切到Joel Levin
Cut to Joel Levin.
他是纽约的一名教师 说服了上级
He’s a teacher in New York who convinced his higher-ups
让他能在计算机课上使用Minecraft
to let him use Minecraft in his computer classes,
而他对学生和老师们对Minecraft的投入程度感到震惊
and he was shocked by how engaged the students and teachers were about Minecraft.
学生们可以学到使用计算机的一般原理
The students could learn the general principles of using computers
比如打字、使用图形界面、以及可视化3D物体
like typing, using GUIs, and visualizing 3D objects,
理论上 他们还能在同一时间学到许多其他学科的知识
and in theory, they could be learning about a number of other subjects at the exact same time.
但与Santeri不同 Joel Levin会说英语
But unlike Santeri, Joel Levin speaks English,
所以当他写博客分享这件事时
so when he makes a blog about it,
真的能上Reddit首页
it actually gets to the Reddit front page.
这行就是这么运作的
That’s just how this works.
他成为了教育Minecraft的代表人物
And he becomes the face of educational Minecraft.
他就是Twitter上的MinecraftTeachr
He’s the MinecraftTeachr on Twitter.
没有字母E 因为他就是这么酷
Without the E because he’s cool like that.
但他遇到了和Santeri类似的问题
But he ran into a similar problem as Santeri.
许多老师想试试这个
Many teachers wanted to try this out,
但它太让人困惑了
but it was too confusing.
他做了一个教程世界、一份模组清单
He made a tutorial world and a mod list
还有很多博客文章 试图向人们解释这个过程
and many blog posts trying to explain the process to people,
但要向一个只用过Acrobat和Yahoo的老师解释 实在是太难了
but it’s really hard to explain to a teacher who has only ever used Acrobat and Yahoo.
哦 而且这样的人有一百个
Oh, and there’s a hundred of them.
要是某地有个人
If only someone, somewhere,
有着丰富的向学生介绍Minecraft的经验
had a lot of experience introducing Minecraft to students,
正在寻找机会制作一个易安装的Minecraft教育模组
and was looking to make a easy-to-install educational mod for Minecraft
而且他们还需要一位有魅力的、受欢迎的英语母语者
and they also needed a popular charismatic native English speaker
来担任公司门面 把他们的理念传播得更远
to be the face of the company to spread their message further.
如果这样的公司存在
And if such a company existed,
那会很酷 如果 比如……
it should be cool if, like…
我不知道 创始人突然莫名其妙地给他们发一条措辞糟糕的推文
I don’t know, the founder just randomly sent them a poorly worded tweet out of the blue.
这是真的
他们开了几次会 Santeri用他
They had a couple of meetings, and Santeri used his
神奇的魅惑之力说服了Joel Levin
magical rizz powers to convince Joel Levin
来他的公司担任教育总监
to work at his company as the Education Director.
虽然他的主要工作是公司的市场营销
And while he mostly did marketing for the company,
但他也是一位经验丰富的老师 知道老师们想要什么
he’s also a very experienced teacher who knows what they would want.
这个三人团队是他们新公司的真正核心
This team of three is the real core of their new company,
TeacherGaming
TeacherGaming.
一个词 因为他们就是这么酷
One word, ’cause they’re cool like that.
我想这也不算新公司
I guess it’s not a new company,
只是Santeri的辅导事业换了个名字
it’s Santeri’s tutoring venture with a different name,
但他们的使命是新的
but their mission is new.
当大多数老师在休假时
While most teachers were on break,
他们正争分夺秒 要在年底前成为一家真正的公司
they were racing to become an actual business by the end of the year.
他们搭建了网站
They set up a website,
找了一位真正的平面设计师设计logo
got an actual graphics designer for the logo,
谢天谢地
thank the fucking lord,
然后开始着手做模组
and then they got working on the mod.
而且由于他们是直接与Mojang合作
And since they were working with Mojang directly,
Jeb亲自给了TeacherGaming
Jeb personally gave TeacherGaming
访问Minecraft全部源代码的权限
access to the entirety of the Minecraft source code.
这些年Minecraft在公开源代码方面慢慢有了进步
Minecraft has slowly gotten better at revealing their source code over the years,
但在当时 这是史无前例的
but at the time, this was unprecedented.
这就好比我想稍微改一下可口可乐
This is like if I wanted to slightly modify Coca-Cola
把它放进我的餐厅里
and put it in my restaurant,
然后三个月后 他们把完整配方给了我
and then three months later they gave me the secret recipe in full.
这太疯狂了
It’s insane.
他们当时还没做完所有功能
They didn’t have quite all of the features done yet,
但在2011年11月1日
but on November 1st, 2011,
他们以测试版的形式发布了MinecraftEdu
they released MinecraftEdu as a beta test.
接下来的几年里
The following years,
Joel频繁出现在大量播客、电台节目和YouTube视频中
Joel would get featured on a ton of podcasts, radio shows, and YouTube videos.
他去了Minecon 2011
He went to Minecon 2011,
Minecon 2012
Minecon 2012,
甚至出现在官方Minecraft纪录片里
and was even in the official Minecraft documentary.
而在这整个过程中
And the whole time,
他一直在推广这个名为  的全新模组
he would be promoting this brand new mod called
MinecraftEdu
MinecraftEdu.
这是一个由教师设计的Minecraft替代版本
It’s an alternate version of Minecraft designed by teachers
供教师在校园环境中与学生一起使用
for teachers to use in a school setting with students.
学校用它来做各种事情
Schools are using it for everything,
从历史
from history,
到数学
to math,
到艺术
to art.
他们可以访问我的网站minecraftedu.com
Well, they can go to my website, minecraftedu.com,
我们有一些入门材料
and we have some materials to get started
还有一些可以用这款游戏做的事情的创意
and some ideas for things you can do with the game.
所有这些媒体报道 说服了许多家长、教职员工和老师：
All of this media coverage would convince many parents, faculty, and teachers that,
嘿 也许我们可以给Minecraft一个机会
hey, maybe we could give Minecraft a shot.
到2012年底 大约有1000所学校决定购买他们的Minecraft模组
By the end of 2012, around about 1,000 schools had decided to buy their Minecraft mod.
等等 什么？等等 抱歉
Wait, what? Wait, sorry
购  购买他们的Minecra
B- buy their Minecra
“购买他们的Minecraft模组”是什么意思？
What do you mean buy their Minecraft mo
出售？
是的 就像To Pimp a Butterfly的第8首曲目一样
Yes, much like track 8 on TPAB,
它是“待售”的
it is For Sale.
如果你不知道的话
If you don’t know,
截至本视频制作之时
as of the making of this video,
Minecraft Java模组是不能用来卖钱的
Minecraft Java mods cannot be sold for money.
不过历史上只有一个例外
There has only ever been one exception, though,
那就是MinecraftEdu
and that is MinecraftEdu.
要让这个模组进入你的教室 要花41美元
It costs $41 to get this mod into your classroom.
这可不便宜 但公平地说 它会持续更新
That’s a lot, but to be fair, it would get updated,
而且整个学校只需要买一份
and you only needed one of them for your entire school.
但这一部分其实还算是便宜的
But that was actually the cheap part.
真正的花费在于你还得购买Minecraft
The real cost came in whenever you had to buy Minecraft.
因为……没错 当然啦
Because… yeah, of course.
这只是一个Minecraft模组
This is just a Minecraft mod,
你仍然得买游戏
you’ve still got to buy the game.
Mojang还允许TeacherGaming以折扣价销售游戏本体
Mojang also allowed TeacherGaming to sell the actual game at a discount.
没错 TeacherGaming还是历史上仅有的
That’s right, TeacherGaming is also one of the only other
官方Minecraft: Java Edition在线零售商之一
official online retailers of Minecraft: Java Edition ever.
我跟你说 Santeri简直就是天赋异禀
I’m telling you, Santeri is just fucking built different.
就是 他  什么都能办成
Like, it  he can get anything done.
任何事
Anything.
世界上任何事！
Anything in the world!
游戏每份18美元
It costs $18 per copy of the game.
或者……你可以花335美元买25份的捆绑包
Or… you could get a bundle of 25 copies for $335,
勉强达到五折优惠
just barely getting it to a 50% discount.
但当然 如果你的学生已经有Minecraft了
But of course, if your students already own Minecraft,
他们其实可以带上自己的个人账号 用它来省点钱
they could actually just bring in their own personal account and use that to save some money.
我不知道该怎么好好算这笔账
I don’t really know of a good way to account for this,
所以从现在起我就假设老师得买下所有账号
so from now on I’m just going to assume that the teacher has to buy all the accounts,
这样比较公平
just to be fair.
那么 要让MinecraftEdu进入你那个有18到25名学生的教室 总花费
So, grand total for getting MinecraftEdu into your classroom of 18 to 25 students,
是376美元
it would cost $376.
老师们通常每年自掏腰包超过500美元
Teachers already usually spend over $500
划掉 实际上是900美元
Uh, scratch that, actually $900
花在教室上
per year out of pocket on their classroom.
正因如此 很多老师不得不说服上级为他们购买
Because of this, a lot of teachers had to convince their higher-ups to buy it for them.
对像Joel Levin这样的人来说
For someone like Joel Levin,
他在曼哈顿一所前卫的预科学校工作
who works at a progressive prep school in Manhattan,
这很容易
this was easy.
每个学生每年要交数万美元的学费才能来这里上学
Each student pays tens of thousands of dollars a year to go here,
所以他们当然买得起一份Minecraft
so you’re damn right they can buy a copy of Minecraft.
但如果你不在曼哈顿的私立学校
But if you aren’t at a private school in Manhattan,
那么连试一下都会增加整整一层的阻力
it adds a whole other layer of friction to even testing this out.
研讨会上很多问题都是关于这个问题的
Many of the questions at the panels were about this exact problem.
当然 “让老师决定它用来做什么”这一点挺讨喜的
Sure, the thing where teachers decide what it’s used for is cute,
但这并不能打动那些
but that doesn’t exactly inspire the staff
在考虑掏钱之前要求先看课程大纲的校方人员
that demand to see a curriculum before they even think about opening their wallet.
但提供课程大纲与他们的整个项目理念相悖
But having a curriculum was against the whole philosophy of their program.
他们想要颠覆学校
They were trying to shake up schools,
所以他们实在没法给出令人满意的答案
so they couldn’t really give them a satisfying answer.
就算你真的过五关斩六将
And even if you do jump through all the hoops,
花了这么多时间和金钱 你也不过是买了个Minecraft
for all of this time and money, you’ve just bought Minecraft.
你仍然需要真正地制作课程
you still need to actually make the lessons.
所以……
So…
值得吗？
好吧 我们不必只看着wiki纸上谈兵
Well, we don’t have to just look at the wiki and theorize,
我们仍然可以安装MinecraftEdu
we can still install MinecraftEdu.
整个系统被专门设计成这样：学校一旦下载了它
The whole system was specifically designed so that once schools downloaded it,
运行它就不需要联网了
they didn’t need an internet connection to run it.
只需要所有人都连在同一个网络里
They just needed to all be on the same network.
他们有一个特殊的启动器来安装MinecraftEdu
They have this special launcher to install MinecraftEdu
它在发布十年后仍然能用
that still works a decade after it was released,
这真的很酷
which is really cool.
登录后 你可以选择名字、性别、装扮
After you log in, you pick your name, gender, outfit,
还可以输入一个秘密代码变成教师
and you can put in a secret code to become a teacher.
我把代码设置成了“点赞订阅”
I set the code to like and subscribe.
这个游戏启动器还兼作服务器启动器
The game launcher also doubles as a server launcher,
真是相当漂亮
which is pretty frickin’ slick.
只要开启服务器 学生们就能通过局域网加入
Just turn on the server and the students can join through LAN.
太棒了
Amazing.
看看这个 他们还放了一个方便的按钮
And look at that, they include a convenient button
用来加载Joel Levin早在2011年做的教程世界
to load Joel Levin’s tutorial world from all the way back in 2011.
我们去看看吧
Let’s go there.
没错 就是它
Yep, this is the one.
他们有一个专门的教师区域
They have this special teacher section,
在这里可以看到所有新方块
and we can see all the new blocks here.
其中很多只是限制学生能做什么
Many of them just restrict what the students can do,
比如允许建造方块和禁止建造方块
like the build allow block and disallow block,
这可能是我这辈子见过最烂的贴图 真的
which may be some of the worst textures that I have ever seen, ever.
只是想提醒你一下 呃
Just want to remind you that, uh,
顺便说一句 这是官方认可的Mojang产品
this is an official Mojang-approved product, by the way.
我想它跟很多老的程序员风格美术挺搭的
It fits with a lot of the old programmer art, I guess.
糟糕的贴图一直延续到这些边界方块上
And the terrible textures continue onto these border blocks
它们防止学生一路跑到天空上限
that prevent students from crossing all the way up to the sky limit.
还有传送方块 可以轻松移动学生
We also get teleporter blocks to move students around easily.
它们的工作原理基本上和Waystones模组一样
They basically work like the Waystones mod.
因为这是为学校准备的
Because this is for school,
传达信息非常重要
relaying information is super important.
但告示牌放不下那么多文字
But signs don’t really hold that much text,
所以自然的解决方案当然是……
so the natural solution is of course…
宽告示牌
wide sign.
这些东西真的在真实模组里我没开玩笑
These are actually in the real mod. I’m not joking.
他们真的只是把告示牌拉宽了
They literally just stretched a sign.
还有这些Slenderman书页 上面可以放海量文字
There are also these Slenderman pages that can hold tons of text on them,
以及大大的“i”方块 用来标示信息所在的位置
and big “i” blocks to show you where information is located.
这里有个视频 一名学生在焚烧一整立方体的它们
Here’s a video of a student burning a gigantic cube of them.
还有一堆数字方块
There’s also a bunch of these number blocks that
我猜是给数学课用的
I guess are supposed to be used for math.
不错 但它只局限于前代数
Cool, but it’s kind of limited to pre-algebra,
因为没有变量
because there aren’t any variables.
大概可以拿一个方块当变量用吧 我猜
Kinda use a block as a variable, I guess.
玩家们 来解方程组吧
Solve the system of equations, gamers.
怎么了？这个视频讲的是学校 所以你有家庭作业
What? This video’s about school, so you get homework.
周一上课前交 赶紧去写
It’s due before class on Monday, get to work.
以上就是所有新增的方块
Those are all of the block additions.
嘿嘿 看到我玩的小把戏了吗？
Heh, see what I did there?
但对老师们来说 还有更多可看的
But there’s a lot more to see for the teachers.
有一套完整的教师控制图形界面
There’s a GUI for a whole set of teacher controls,
这样他们就不必输入命令了
so they don’t have to type out commands.
其中有些功能甚至比基础游戏更早加入MinecraftEdu
And a couple of these were added to MinecraftEdu before they even made it into the base game.
从这里你还可以冻结游戏、禁止学生建造、
From here you could also freeze the game, disable student building,
布置作业、把所有人传送到出生点、静音所有学生、给所有学生发物品
add assignments, teleport everyone to spawn, mute all students, give all students items,
等等等等
and so on.
老师们还可以使用一套建造工具
Teachers also have access to a suite of building tools
一次性放置或移除大量方块
to place or remove tons of blocks at once.
既然不能把WorldEdit给老师们用
Since they couldn’t give WorldEdit to teachers,
他们只好重制其中最重要的部分
they needed to remake the most important parts.
这玩意儿怎么还是比现在Minecraft里的/fill命令好用？
How is this still better than the /fill command in current Minecraft?
我不知道
I don’t know.
就MinecraftEdu模组本身而言 就这些了
And as far as the MinecraftEdu mod is concerned, that’s it.
进去用这些工具制作你自己的课程吧
Go in and use these tools to make your own lessons.
因为这个模组不附带任何课程
Because there are no lessons that come with this mod,
你必须全部自己做
you have to make all of them.
MinecraftEdu的前期成本真的很高
MinecraftEdu is really expensive up front,
无论是时间还是金钱
both in terms of time and money.
就算你有WorldEdit
Even if you have WorldEdit,
做起来还是要花不少时间
it still takes a while,
而且不是每个老师都是游戏设计师
and not every teacher is a game designer.
他们不可能每天都坚持做 实在是太花时间了
They can’t possibly do it every single day consistently, it just takes too long.
而且除此之外 还要近400美元
And then on top of that, it’s nearly $400.
就算你闯过所有这些难关
And even if you jump through all of these hoops,
你仍然需要浪费好几节课来讲解它
you still need to waste multiple classes explaining it.
你需要一群好老师
You need a bunch of good teachers,
而且你需要用特定的方式来教学 它才能真正起作用
and you need to teach in a specific way for it to actually work.
它的定价好像它能取代你整个教室
It’s priced as though it will replace your entire classroom,
但实际上要做到这一点太花时间了
but in practice it takes too much time to actually do that.
在完整发布MinecraftEdu之后
After releasing MinecraftEdu fully,
他们陷入了困境
they were in a predicament.
他们想添加更多内容让产品更值
They wanted to add more content to make it more worth it,
但那会让本已高昂的价格更高
but that would increase the price higher than it already is.
怎样才能在不花大钱的情况下 为客户提供更多价值呢？
How do you provide more value to your customers without spending a bunch of money?
让社区来做！
2013年底 Teacher Gaming发布了MinecraftEdu世界库
In late 2013, Teacher Gaming released the MinecraftEdu World Library.
这是一个网站 老师们可以在上面上传自己的世界供他人使用
This was a website where teachers could upload their own worlds for others to use.
运营三年后 它总共只有172个世界
After three years of uptime, it had a grand total of 172 worlds.
在同一时期 PlanetMinecraft上
During that same timeframe on PlanetMinecraft,
千张地图被上传
thousand maps were uploaded.
那172张地图中 有多少是
How many of those 172 maps are the exact
恰好符合你课堂的科目、课程大纲和教学风格？
subject, curriculum, and teaching style for your classroom?
没有那么多
Not that many.
但它们通过大部分世界质量不错来弥补这一点
But they make up for it by most of the worlds being pretty good.
像乘法竞速、Minecraft妙探寻凶、绵羊概率、
Worlds like Multiplication Race, Minecraft Clue, Sheep Probability,
人文世界和动物细胞之旅都是这份列表中的亮点
The World of Humanities, and Animal Cell Tour are highlights on this list.
当然 里面也有不少模板世界
Sure, there’s your fair share of just, like, template worlds
还有一些明显是学生上传的
and ones that were clearly uploaded by a student,
但总体来说 质量相当稳定地高
but overall, it’s pretty consistently high quality.
如果你在这里上传世界
If you uploaded here,
那你真的很在乎其他老师能不能从中获得一堂好课
you actually cared about other teachers getting a good lesson out of it.
不像本视频后面会提到的某些其他库
Unlike some other libraries that will be mentioned later in this video.
本着让社区帮忙的这一思路
In this vein of getting the community to help,
他们还有一个谷歌群组
they also had a Google Group.
我以前从没听说过谷歌群组
I’ve never heard of a Google Group before,
但它基本上就是一个群组、邮件、论坛……
but it’s basically like a group, email, forum…
以及其他一些莫名其妙的互联网词汇缝合怪
other unc internet-type word abomination.
这个群组里大约有3600人
There are about 3600 people in this group,
而且里面似乎有很多人愿意帮助别人
and it seems like there’s a lot of people ready to help others out in there.
这真的非常棒 而且是免费的
This is genuinely really cool, and it was free.
我提到这个群组 是因为在MinecraftEdu最初的公告帖中
I mention this group because in the initial announcement post for MinecraftEdu,
他们说要为你和你的同事提供现场研讨会和在职培训
they said that they would offer on-site workshops and in-service training
for you and your colleagues.
但据我所知
As far as I can tell though,
这从来没有真正发生过
this never actually happened.
我的游戏理论猜测是 这个谷歌群组是在技术上实现这一点的一种更省钱的方式
My Game Theory is that this Google Group was a cheaper way to technically do this,
连同他们自己的个人wiki
along with their own personal wiki.
本频道很爱wiki
We love wikis on this channel.
它们是让社区团结起来
They’re a great way for the community to band together
传播经过同行评审的信息
to spread peer-reviewed information.
让我们来看看 然后
Let’s check it out, and
哦 你必须经过个人审批才能编辑这个wiki
Oh, you have to be personally approved to edit this wiki.
所以社区其实根本帮不上忙
So the community can’t really help at all,
因为Joel Levin显然害怕被恶意破坏？
because Joel Levin is apparently scared of vandalism?
拜托 开放编辑才是wiki变好的方式
Girl, it being open is how the wiki gets better.
这就是人们贡献的原因
That’s, like, why people contribute.
而且 它根本就不是MediaWiki
Also, it’s not a MediaWiki at all,
只是一些专有软件
it’s just some proprietary software.
而且那些页面的排版也完全不像wiki条目
And the pages aren’t really formatted like wiki articles at all,
更像是FAQ（常见问题解答）
they’re more like a FAQ.
这个wiki一团糟
This wiki’s a mess.
Joel 你觉得呢？
What do you think about it, Joel?
但我要说句大实话
But I’ll be brutally honest here,
我个人认为这个wiki一团糟
I personally think the wiki’s a mess.
是的 没错 它很糟糕
Yeah, no, it’s not good.
问题的一大来源是服务器方面
One big source of issues was the server aspect.
不是所有老师都恰好是网络专家
Not all teachers just so happen to be networking experts,
即便对专家来说
and even for someone who is,
它有时候也会随机地决定不想工作
it just randomly decides that it doesn’t want to work sometimes,
哪怕是在拍相关视频的时候
even while filming a video about it.
要是能花钱请别人来替我处理服务器问题就好了
If only I could pay someone else to deal with the server issues instead of me.
隆重推出MinecraftEdu托管服务！
Introducing the MinecraftEdu hosting service!
每月只需一张Andrew Jackson（20美元）
For one Andrew Jackson per month,
你就能租一台托管MinecraftEdu的Minecraft服务器
you could rent a Minecraft server that would host MinecraftEdu.
它永远在线 会备份你的世界
It would always be online, back up your worlds,
并把它们全部存储起来以便快速切换
and store them all for quick switching.
但在你刚付的那些钱之上 它还是太贵了
But it is so expensive on top of the amount you just paid,
有点离谱
it’s kind of insane.
自然而然 2016年 他们下调了
Naturally, in 2016, they lowered
抱歉 我的意思是
sorry, I mean
他们把价格上调了一张Abraham Lincoln（5美元）
raised the price by adding Abraham Lincoln into the equation.
行吧 挺好的
Cool, I guess.
为了让交易更诱人 他们还增加了一项：模组支持
One more extra that was added to sweeten the deal was modding.
MinecraftEdu发布时Forge还没流行起来
MinecraftEdu came out before Forge was popular,
所以当他们确定Forge不是一时热潮后 模组不得不迁移过去
so the mod had to be moved over there once they knew that Forge was not just a fad.
所以现在你可以在MinecraftEdu旁边安装任何其他Forge模组
So now you can install any other Forge mod alongside MinecraftEdu.
他们还内置了一个完整的模组管理器
And they built in a whole mod manager
可以在里面启用或禁用已安装的模组
where you could enable and disable the mods that you had installed.
除此之外 Teacher Gaming还制作了
On top of this, Teacher Gaming also created
针对特定科目的自定附加模组
their own custom additional mods for certain subjects.
ComputerCraft模组是由Daniel Ratcliffe制作的
The mod ComputerCraft was made by Daniel Ratcliffe.
不 不是那个
No, not that one.
dan200
dan200.
他参与过Kinectimals的开发 好吗？
He worked on Kinectimals, okay?
对他的名字放尊重点
Put some respect on his name.
这个模组让你可以给这些海龟编程 让它们做任何你想做的事
This is the mod that lets you code these little turtles to do whatever you want.
它出了名的看起来超酷
It’s famous for looking super cool
然后又让孩子们哭出来 因为
and then making kids cry because,
哎呀 你没法凭空就会用Lua编程
aw, you can’t magically code in Lua,
你***白痴
you fucking idiot.
哦 好吧 看来你就是个废物
Oh, well, I guess you’re a fucking failure.
****
Fuck you.
不是说我自己经历过这些
Not that I’ve experienced that or anything.
幸运的是 ComputerCraftEdu试图解决这个问题
Luckily, ComputerCraftEdu tries to fix this problem
它新增了一只新手海龟 可以用拖拽式编程语言来编程
by adding a new beginner turtle that you can program with a drag-and-drop coding language.
听起来很酷 直到你看到它并开始想
Sounds cool until you look at it and start to think,
也许用Lua编程其实也没那么糟糕
maybe coding in Lua isn’t that bad, actually.
你可以给海龟添加小装饰和名字
You can add little cosmetics and names to the turtles,
它们绝对萌翻了
which are absolutely adorable.
她叫Denise 也许看起来平平无奇
Her name is Denise, and she may look basic,
但她的内部构造复杂得惊人
but she is insanely complicated on the inside.
不过 这还不是唯一的附加模组
This wasn’t the only extra mod, though.
TeacherGaming和dan200合作制作了一个模组 与……
TeacherGaming and dan200 collaborated on making a mod with,
呃……
uh…
加州理工和谷歌？？
California Tech and Google??
哇 好吧
Wow, okay.
它叫qCraft
It’s called qCraft.
Minecraft太棒了 量子物理称霸！
Minecraft rocks, quantum rules!
它加入了一些模糊模拟量子力学的方块
It adds blocks that vaguely resemble quantum mechanics
在你观察它们时发生变化
by changing when you observe them.
这是个可以拿来向别人炫耀的酷模组 好说
It’s a cool mod to be able to show off to people to say,
哇 你能相信我的二年级学生正在通过Minecraft学习量子物理吗？
wow, can you believe that my second-graders are learning quantum physics through Minecraft?
这真是太有教育意义、太神奇了
This is so educational and amazing.
但归根结底 它更像是一种“我们做到了”的噱头
Ultimately, though, it kind of just feels like a gimmick to say that they did it,
而不是真正能帮助老师和学生的东西
rather than anything that actually helps teachers or students.
我觉得有些其他游戏在量子物理方面做得比这好得多
I think that some other games have done quantum much better than this.
而且 呃……
And, uh…
我重  我喜欢这个玩笑
I re– I like this joke.
我希望你们能体会到为了这个我准备了多久
I hope you acknowledge how long this took me to set up,
但它解析起来太慢了
but it takes a bit too long to resolve,
所以我只是在拖时间……
so I’m just kind of stalling…
好了 行 搞定了
Okay, cool, we’re done.
和ComputerCraftEdu不同
Unlike ComputerCraftEdu,
他们不能把这个和主模组捆绑在一起
they couldn’t bundle this with the main mod,
而只是把它放在网站上供手动安装
and instead just put it on their website to install manually.
我真想知道为什么Mojang不愿意和谷歌合作
I sure do wonder why Mojang was trying not to work with Google.
嗯 我不知道 真奇怪
Hmm, I don’t know, weird.
好的 我现在完成了这个过渡
而就模组周边的一切而言
And as far as everything surrounding the mod goes,
也就这些了
that is finally it.
那它现在值得吗？
Is it worth it now?
嗯 对很多学校来说 答案是肯定的
Well, for a lot of schools, the answer was yes.
你好 我叫Santeri Koivisto
Hello, my name is Santeri Koivisto,
我是TeacherGaming的首席执行官
I’m the CEO of TeacherGaming.
我们现在与40个国家的6000多所学校合作
We now work with over 6,000 schools in 40 different countries,
我们喜欢称自己是教育领域的变革推动者之一
and we like to call ourselves one of the changemakers in the educational field.
但是 当你主动违背学校的常规运作方式时
But, when you’re actively going against how schools normally operate,
大多数学校只会拒绝你
most schools will just reject you.
老师们多年来一直要求某种课程大纲
Teachers asked for years for some kind of curriculum
或者能实时追踪学生行为的方法
or ways to track what their students are doing as they’re doing it,
但他们真的给不了
but they literally couldn’t give it to them,
因为他们想当变革推动者
because they wanted to be the changemakers.
这不是学校
This isn’t school,
我们活在社会中
we’re living in a society.
许多老师要求支持其他设备 而不只是
Many teachers asked for support for devices other than just
PC、Mac和Linux
PC, Mac, and Linux,
比如教室里越来越流行的Chromebook和iPad
like the increasingly popular Chromebooks and iPads in classrooms.
但他们做不到
But they couldn’t do that,
因为这个模组是基于Java版构建的
because this mod was built off of Java Edition.
所有这些人都立刻被排除在外了
All those people were just instantly cut off.
这些是他们战略中固有的问题 会阻碍大规模采用
These were innate problems with their strategy that would prevent mass adoption.
这意味着这基本上只会是一个噱头
Which means that this would basically just be a gimmick,
而不是什么教育革命
rather than some kind of educational revolution.
如果他们能从头再来
If they could restart from scratch,
他们可能会做得大不一样
they would probably do things pretty differently.
有一家公司一直在暗处观察
And there’s one company that’s been watching from the shadows
并且认为他们知道该怎么做
and thinks that they know how to do that.
而他们的计划始于那个2014年9月的
And their plan starts with the huge, earth-shattering,
被我一带而过的惊天动地的大事件
gigantic event in September of 2014 that I skimmed over:
TeacherGaming参加ALS冰桶挑战
TeacherGaming doing the ALS Ice Bucket Challenge.
有趣的是 他们的视频里没有冰
Funnily enough, their video doesn’t contain ice.
也没有桶
Or a bucket.
哦 而且第二天
Oh, and the next day,
微软宣布要收购Mojang
Microsoft announced that they were going to buy Mojang.
Santeri知道他们需要多元化发展
Santeri knew that they needed to diversify,
但他们觉得船到桥头自然直
but they figured that they would just cross that bridge when they came to it.
随便吧
Whatever.
呃 好吧 它来了
Uh, well, it’s here.
当然 眼下它其实影响不到他们
Sure, right now it doesn’t really affect them.
但他们的协议怎么办？
But what about their agreement?
如果收购成真 Minecraft的未来会变成什么样？
How is Minecraft going to look in the future if this happens?
微软还会那么愿意让TeacherGaming查看Minecraft源代码吗？
Will Microsoft be as willing to let TeacherGaming look at the Minecraft source code?
或者卖他们的模组？
Or sell their mod?
或者卖Minecraft本体？
Or sell Minecraft itself?
如果Minecraft就这么消亡了会怎样？
What would happen if Minecraft just died out?
它的人气开始下滑
Its popularity was starting to fall,
而且它即将归微软所有
and it’s about to be owned by Microsoft,
那个万物杀手
the killers of everything.
有传言说将有一个新版本的Minecraft完全取代Java版
There are rumors of a new version of Minecraft that would replace Java Edition entirely.
如果它消失了
And if it goes away,
那他们到底该怎么办？
then what the heck are they going to even do?
哦不
Oh no.
看看他们的产品组合
Looking at their portfolio,
他们有MinecraftEdu以及与之相关的所有东西
they have MinecraftEdu and all the things that go along with it,
他们还有一个坎巴拉太空计划的教育版 叫做
they’ve got an educational version of Kerbal Space Program called
说出来你都不信
and you’re not going to believe this
KerbalEdu
KerbalEdu,
然后……就没了
and… that’s it.
如果明天Minecraft死了 他们就完蛋了
If Minecraft dies tomorrow, they’re fucked.
他们刚被一桶“冰”水浇脸 猛然惊醒
They just took an ALS ice bucket to the face and woke up.
他们必须多元化
They need to diversify.
最好是昨天就开始
Like, yesterday.
他们打算怎么做呢？
How are they going to do that?
嗯 要回答这个问题
Well, to answer that question,
Santeri必须回到他的初心
Santeri had to go back to his roots.
2011年3月 Santeri在自己的个人博客上写道
In March of 2011, Santeri wrote on his own personal blog that
“如果我是软件公司的老板”
“if I were the boss of a software company”
他现在确实是了
which he is now
“下一个项目将是一个全面的电子‘学习与教学环境’
“the next project would be a comprehensive electronic ‘learning and teaching environment’
把老师们日常生活中的所有零散部分和管理整合起来
which would include all the scattered pieces and management of the daily lives of teachers,
全部装进一扇门里”
all into one door.”
然后还有什么关于“金色雨”的东西？
And then something about golden showers?
我不知道那
I don’t know wh– it’s
管他呢 呃……
Whatever. Uh…
这不是什么好选择
It wasn’t a great option,
但这是他们避免落得两手空空的最佳机会
but this was their best chance to not be left holding the bag.
TeacherGaming的创始人们很快创办了一家新公司
The creators of TeacherGaming quickly founded a new company,
再多五分钟有限公司
Five More Minutes Limited.
这个名字放在这儿真是恰如其分
The name really fits here.
他们的目标是制作一款名为TeacherGaming Desk的新桌面应用
Their goal is to make a new desktop app called TeacherGaming Desk.
他们联系了一堆游戏公司
They contacted a bunch of gaming companies,
并利用他们在MinecraftEdu上的影响力
and using their clout with MinecraftEdu,
说服他们让TG Desk以教育折扣价向学校出售游戏
convinced them to let TG Desk sell their games to schools at an educational discount.
他们吹嘘的最酷功能是 这个桌面应用
The coolest feature that they touted was that the desk app
能够透视游戏内部 追踪学生的进度
would be able to look inside the game and track the progression of your students,
这样他们在游玩时 你可以自动看到
so as they played, you could automatically see
他们在学习美国课程标准中的哪些部分
which parts of the United States curriculum they were learning.
还有他们做MinecraftEdu时的那个取舍
There’s also that trade-off that they had with MinecraftEdu.
开发者做的工作越多 老师要付的价格就越高
The more work for the developers means a higher price for the teacher.
现在开发者必须手动进入游戏集成代码
Now the devs have to manually go in and integrate code into the game
才能实现那些酷炫的课程追踪
to do all the cool curriculum tracking.
如果你想用一大套游戏来覆盖大量课程内容
If you want a large set of games to represent a lot of the curriculum,
那价格很快就会变得非常昂贵
that’s gonna get real expensive real quick,
而价签也反映了这一点
and the price tag reflects that.
哦太好了 是订阅制
Oh great, it’s a subscription model.
耶耶耶
Yayyy.
我敢肯定这绝不会反噬他们！
I’m sure that won’t come back to bite them!
这里我们可以看到 他们对学校的态度发生了非常明显的转变
There’s a very distinct shift that we can see here in their attitude towards school.
MinecraftEdu希望学校改变
MinecraftEdu wanted schools to change,
让学生在课堂上有更多自主权
to give students more agency in lessons,
更亲自动手、更高参与度、教数字公民素养、教协作
to be more hands-on, higher-engagement, teach digital citizenship, teach collaboration,
并展望21世纪的学校能教授的新东西
and look forward to the new things that the 21st century schools could teach.
但TG Desk似乎更想顺应学校目前的现状
But TG Desk seems like they more want to be alongside school as it is currently.
但即使这违背了Santeri最初相信的一切
But even though it goes against all of the things that Santeri believed in the beginning,
这至少能在他们无法再做MinecraftEdu时缓冲一下打击
it’s at least something to cushion the blow if they can’t make MinecraftEdu anymore.
而在2015年底 这恰恰就发生了
And in late 2015, that was exactly what happened.
微软向Teacher Gaming发来报价 要花一大笔钱买下整个MinecraftEdu
Microsoft sent an offer to Teacher Gaming to buy all of MinecraftEdu for a lot of money.
幸运的是 他们现在对此已有准备
Luckily, they were prepared for this now.
他们有新应用了
They had their new app,
Minecraft的人气仍在下降
Minecraft was still declining in popularity,
他们做出了艰难的决定 是时候放手了
and they made the tough decision that it was time to let go,
他们不再需要Minecraft了
that they didn’t need Minecraft anymore.
交易达成了
The deal went through,
现在微软拥有了MinecraftEdu的所有部分
and now Microsoft is in possession of all parts of MinecraftEdu:
模组、网站、世界库
the mod, the website, the world library,
甚至那个不是wiki的wiki
even the wiki that wasn’t a wiki.
2016年7月1日
On July 1st, 2016,
Joel Levin宣布他将离开Five More Minutes
Joel Levin announced that he was leaving Five More Minutes
回去全职教书
and going back to teaching full-time.
作为回应 他把自己的Twitter账号改成了GamerTeachr
In response, he changed his Twitter handle to GamerTeachr.
依然没有字母E
still without the E,
因为他依然那么酷
because he’s still cool like that.
不过 其他大多数员工都留在了船上
Most of the other employees stayed on the ship, though,
他们准备好看看Five More Minutes会把他们带向何方
and they were ready to see where Five More Minutes would sail them.
再见各位 玩得开心！
Bye guys, have fun!
呃 总之 你们刚才在说什么？
Uh, anyway, what were y’all saying?
微软正在收购MinecraftEdu
Microsoft is acquiring MinecraftEdu,
并投资于一个全新且扩展的教室版Minecraft
and investing in a new and expanded version of Minecraft for the classroom,
名为我的世界：教育版
called Minecraft: Education Edition.
微软一直在暗中
Microsoft has been in the shadows,
研究TeacherGaming是怎么做MinecraftEdu的
studying how TeacherGaming made MinecraftEdu,
并想从头重做一遍
and wanted to redo it from scratch.
首先 这是基于基岩版的全新版本
First of all, this is a brand new version on top of Minecraft: Bedrock Edition.
因此 MinecraftEdu将被彻底淘汰
Because of that, MinecraftEdu is being sunsetted entirely.
你为它制作的所有世界都将被困在1.8.9版本……
All of your worlds that you made for it are going to be stuck in version 1.8.9…
永远
Forever.
而且 额外“福利” 你上传到MinecraftEdu世界库的任何地图
And bonus any maps that you uploaded to the MinecraftEdu World Library
那些你为了帮助其他老师而上传的
to, you know, help out other teachers
现在也都归微软所有了
are now also owned by Microsoft.
所以 希望你们对此没意见
So, hope you’re all good with that.
但别担心 MinecraftEdu用户们！
But do not worry, MinecraftEDUsers!
为了感谢你们的光顾
For your patronage,
你们可以免费获得教育版！
you get Minecraft: Education Edition for free!
哦 等等 不 抱歉
Oh. Wait, no, sorry,
你们获得的是……
you get the…
第一年免费？
first year for free?
哦
Oh.
哦不
Oh no.
教育版Minecraft现在采用了大家最爱的商业模式
Educational Minecraft is now everyone’s favorite business model:
订阅服务
a subscription service.
每个学生每年5美元才能使用教育版
Five dollars per year per student to use Minecraft: Education Edition.
但这不是获得它的唯一方式
But that’s not the only way to get it.
Minecraft教育版也包含在微软面向全校的Office 365套餐中
Minecraft Education is also included in Microsoft’s school-wide Office 365 plans.
这些套餐基本上是让管理员为整个学校开通Office产品的访问权限
They’re basically for the administrators to give your entire school access to Office products.
你至少要拥有A1套餐 才能以每年5美元的价格
You must have at least A1 to be able to rent Minecraft: Education Edition
租用教育版
at that five-dollars-a-year price.
但如果你有A3或A5 它就包含在内
But if you have A3 or A5, it comes included.
但我的重点是 你无法购买教育版
But my point is that you cannot buy Minecraft: Education Edition.
你必须永远从微软那里租用它
You need to rent it from Microsoft forever.
我还想指出 在Minecraft基岩版中
And I do want to note that in Minecraft Bedrock
你可以启用教育功能
you can enable educational features,
但这些与Minecraft教育版的功能并不相同
but these are not the same as the Minecraft Education features.
有很多东西缺失
There are a lot of things that are missing
这让它们对老师来说更难用了 总之谢谢再见
and it makes them way, way harder for teachers to use anyway thank you bye.
而且我其实认为 理论上
And I actually think that in theory,
这种订阅模式对老师和微软双方来说其实都可能是好事
this subscription model could actually be a good thing for both teachers and Microsoft.
但现实情况是
But the reality of the situation
它烂透了
is that it’s shit.
对老师来说
For teachers.
当然 对微软来说不是
Not for Microsoft, of course.
开始使用Minecraft教育版的费用已经大幅下降
The price to start using Minecraft Education has significantly gone down,
这让老师更有可能
which makes it a lot more likely that
自己去试一试 看看情况如何
a teacher could test it out on their own and see what’s happening.
他们利用了这样一个事实 大多数老师不会把Minecraft
They lean into the fact that most teachers aren’t going to be using Minecraft
当作主要教学工具
as their main teaching apparatus.
每月10.42美元 就能让全班25名学生使用教育版
It is $10.42 a month to get your entire class of 25 to use Minecraft: Education Edition.
Spotify Premium都比这贵
Spotify Premium is more expensive than that.
而且有了更稳定的收入流
And with a more constant revenue stream,
理论上他们就有能力投入更多工作 为游戏添加课程和功能
they could hypothetically afford to do more work on adding lessons and features to the game,
而不是让社区做所有事
rather than getting the community to do everything.
所以这肯定意味着教育版
So surely this means that Minecraft: Education Edition
会更物有所值吧 毕竟它显然值无限多的钱 对吧？
will be better value since it’s apparently worth infinite money, right?
那么 为了这个视频
Well, for this video,
我租了教育版 这样你们就不必租了
I rented Education Edition so that you do not have to.
相信我 你们也不该租
And trust me, you shouldn’t.
让我们去看看这里面到底是什么情况
Let’s go see what’s actually going on in here.
嗯 首先 一个你可能没想到的加分项是
Well, first of all, something you might not have thought of as a bonus
它是基于基岩版构建的
is that it’s built off of Bedrock Edition.
所以基岩版支持的所有操作系统它都支持
So it’s on every single operating system that Bedrock is on.
是的 PC上有 还有iPad、Chromebook和其他移动设备上也有
Yes, on PCs, but also iPads and Chromebooks and other mobile processors.
这自动成为他们对比MinecraftEdu的一大优势
That’s automatically a huge advantage they have over MinecraftEdu.
但与此同时
But at the same time,
基于基岩版也算是一种劣势
being on Bedrock Edition is kind of a disadvantage,
因为它基本上是游戏的降智版本
because it’s basically a dumbed-down version of the game,
而且在很多方面都很糟糕
and it’s terrible in so many different ways,
但我们在这里就不必细说了
but we don’t really need to get into that here.
有趣的事实 他们每年只更新一次教育版
Fun fact: they only update Minecraft: Education Edition once per year.
当我们获得Chase the Skies更新时
As we got the Chase the Skies drop,
他们获得的是特别的Chase the Clouds更新
they got the special Chase the Clouds update,
那里面包含了当年之前所有的更新
which had all of the drops before it that year.
这其实说得通
This actually makes sense.
老师们不想也不需要每三个月更新一次
Teachers don’t want or need to update every three months.
至于实际功能
As for actual features,
有很多专门关于化学的新增内容
there’s a lot of additions specifically about chemistry.
你可以把方块分解成元素
You can decompose blocks into elements,
用原子粒子制作自己的原子
make your own atoms with atomic particles,
用这些原子合成化合物 制作自定义方块和物品 比如水下TNT
make compounds from those atoms to construct custom blocks and items like underwater TNT.
你可以制作小冰弹 扮演Kelvin Deadlock
You can make little ice bombs to cosplay Kelvin Deadlock.
这座城市是我的游乐场！
This city is my playground!
甚至可以做一个大象牙膏实验！
And even do an elephant toothpaste reaction!
你大概会从大约两年前Gneiss Name的这个视频里认识其中很多内容
You might know a lot of these from this Gneiss Name video from about two years ago now.
他对教育版提出了很多抱怨
He levied a lot of complaints about Minecraft: Education Edition,
第一个就是关于物质分解器产生的元素
and the very first one was about the elements from the material reducer.
基本上 这个游戏里有一些真实的岩石
Basically there are real rocks in this game,
比如安山岩 它是以现实中的真实山脉命名的
like andesite, which is named after a real mountain range in real life.
但每当你把这些岩石放进物质分解器
But whenever you put those rocks into the material reducer,
它们给出的并不是现实中这些岩石应有的成分
they don’t give you what the actual real life rocks would be.
这是一个巨大的错失良机
This is a huge missed opportunity
没能让学生通过Minecraft学习地质学和化学
to let the students learn about geology and chemistry through Minecraft.
于是他为此做了一个视频
So he made a video about it,
并详细列出了现实中这些岩石
and laid out a whole section about all of the elements
所含的所有元素
that the rocks are made out of in real life.
对他们来说 本来只需要
It would have been so easy for them to literally just
把这些从镜头里复制粘贴进游戏就行了 多么简单
copy and paste those from this shot into the game.
你猜怎么着？
And guess what?
过去两年他们一直没这么做
They haven’t done that for the last two years.
一切都还是错的
Everything is still in there wrong.
依然没有新方块
There are still none of the new blocks.
比如说 真真切切的铜
Like, literal copper.
我不是化学家 但我很确定铜就是铜
I’m no chemist, but I’m pretty sure that copper is copper.
如果Gneiss两年都没能让这件事得到改正
If Gneiss can’t get this changed over two years,
老实说 我不认为它还会发生
I don’t think it’s going to happen, to be honest,
因为他们根本不在乎
because they don’t fucking care.
正如他在视频中所说
And as he said in his video,
这正在实实在在地阻碍学习
this is actively impeding learning
让那些想用最爱的电子游戏学习的学生和老师感到困惑
by confusing students and teachers who might try to learn with their favorite video game.
好吧 我们还是继续吧
Okay, let’s just move on.
继续吧
Let’s just move on.
看看教育版独占的方块
Looking at the blocks that are exclusive to Minecraft: Education Edition,
我们能看到很多与Edu版相似之处
we see a lot of parallels with Edu.
控制方块在新版本中都有对应物
The control blocks all have equivalents in the new version,
谢天谢地 这次贴图好了一些
thankfully with some better textures this time.
说这话让我很痛心
And it pains me to say,
但宽告示牌没了
but the wide signs are dead.
取而代之的是这些有三种不同名字的黑板类东西
In their place are these chalkboard things that have three different names,
这让它们极难被搜索到
which make them terrible to search up.
而每当你加载包含它们的课程时
And whenever you load a lesson with them in it,
它们全都坏了 还朝着错误的方向
they’re all broken and facing the wrong way.
我  我不知道你怎么能漏掉这种事
I– I don’t know how you miss something like that.
就像 这  这是什么？
Like, what– what is this?
如果你想试着复刻在MinecraftEdu上的课程 你什么材料都有
You’ve got all the materials if you want to try and recreate lessons that you had on MinecraftEdu,
但你只能非常缓慢地一点点加回来
but you’ll have to add them all back really slowly
因为没有与MinecraftEdu快速建造工具对应的东西
because there is no equivalent to the fast building tools from MinecraftEdu.
你可以用那个糟糕的/fill命令 我猜
You can use the terrible /fill command, I guess,
但Edu做出那些工具 就是为了让老师不必和命令打交道
but Edu made those tools so that teachers wouldn’t have to deal with commands.
哇 就好像他们根本不在乎似的
Wow, it’s like they don’t care or something.
不过还有不少方块没有对应物
There are quite a few blocks that have no equivalents though,
比如数字方块
like the number blocks,
“i”方块
the “i” block
这孩子会很高兴
this kid would be happy
而非常遗憾的是 所有qCraft方块和物品也没能保留下来
and very sadly, all of the qCraft blocks and items didn’t make it either.
看来量子也没能称霸多久
I guess quantum didn’t rule that much.
作为海龟的替代品 有智能体
And as a replacement for the turtles, there is the agent.
只不过 天哪
Except, oh my god,
他们真的有像样的拖拽式编程
they actually have good drag and drop code.
如果你做过“编程一小时”活动 这个你可能会觉得眼熟
This might look familiar to you if you ever did the hour of code
抱歉 是“AI一小时”
sorry, hour of AI
在学生时代
back in school.
他们还为老师提供了一个单独的程序 叫“教室模式”
They also give teachers a separate program called classroom mode.
它给你一张大地图 你可以实时看到每个学生在哪里
It gives you this big map and you can see where every student is in real time,
你还可以把游戏规则调整改成图形界面操作
and you can change game rules to the GUI.
我得承认 这挺酷的
I gotta admit, it’s pretty cool.
挺酷的
It’s pretty cool.
最好的新功能是相机
The best new feature is the camera.
它们显然比不上我的相机
They’re nothing compared to my cameras obviously,
因为它们不能拍视频
because they don’t shoot video.
但学生可以拍摄他们在课堂上的成果
But students can take pictures of what they did in class
并把它们放进新的作品集里
and put them into their new portfolio.
课堂结束后
Once you’re done in class,
你只要把作品集导出为PDF
you just export the portfolio to a PDF
然后交给老师
and turn it into your teacher.
老师们需要能够向管理者展示
Teachers need to be able to show administrators that
游戏里确实有实实在在的事情在发生
things are actually tangibly happening in the game,
而这是一个很好的方式
and that’s a great way to do that.
不过这确实让我有点恼火
It does piss me off slightly though,
因为它表明他们早就把书与笔做得很好了
because it shows that they’ve already made books and quills good,
但只限于这个愚蠢的教育版游戏
but it’s only for this stupid educational version of the game.
把那功能带到Java版啊 拜托！
Bring that to Java, come on!
他们帮助老师的另一种方式是提供一个课程库
Another way that they help teachers is by having a lesson library.
是的 它和MinecraftEdu世界库非常相似
Yes, it is very similar to the MinecraftEdu world library,
只不过它在创新方面更进一步 变得更烂
except it’s innovating by being even worse.
一些由微软官方制作的世界真的非常棒
Some of the worlds that are officially made by Microsoft are genuinely really good.
比如这个AI侦探主题的
Like this AI detective one,
向学生展示在我们的生成式AI……时代
showing students how to tell what is real in our gen-AI…
如何辨别真假
situation.
虽然其中一些世界只是平坦地图中间立着一块告示牌
And while some of these worlds are just a sign in the middle of a flat map,
总的来说 这个库里的世界质量高于MinecraftEdu上的
in general the worlds in this library are higher-quality than the ones on MinecraftEdu,
但前提是它们真的有世界
but that’s only if they actually have a world.
要知道 这是课程库
Ya know, this is a lesson library,
不是世界库
not a world library,
所以你根本不需要有世界
so you don’t need to have a world at all.
比如这个IGCSE地理目标3.5·能源
Like the IGCSE GEOGRAPHY OBJ 3.5 ENERGY,
里面只是写着
where it just says,
让您的学生在Minecraft里建造一座发电厂
have your students build a power plant in Minecraft.
祝你好运 废物
Good luck, loser.
如果你在想 哦
And if you’re thinking, oh,
我只要筛选出那些真的有世界的就行
I’ll just filter for the ones that actually do have a world,
嘿 想得美 因为如果你试着那么做
heh, nice try, because if you try to do that,
它会说它们其实全都没有世界
it says that none of them have any worlds actually,
是你在凭空想象
you’re imagining things.
非常酷 顺便说一下 这可要花无限多的钱
Very cool. By the way, this costs infinite money.
你们知道吗？
Are you aware of this?
这让我很自然地进入下一个部分
That brings me nicely to the next part of this,
那就是筛选功能根本不能用
is that the filters don’t fucking work.
在Gneiss的视频里
In Gneiss’s video,
他建议他们增加一个按语言筛选这些世界的功能
he suggested that they add a way to filter these worlds by language,
因为其中很多不是英语
because a lot of them are not in English.
看看 他们真的加了 太疯狂了！
And look at that, they actually added that, that’s crazy!
我喜欢公司听取社区意见的时候
I love when companies listen to the community.
给我看看所有英语的历史课
Show me all of the history lessons in English.
呃 第二个结果是希腊语的解剖课
Uh, the second result is an anatomy lesson in Greek.
公平地说 这个被标注为英语
To be fair, this one is listed as being in English,
大概是创作者不小心标错了
probably by accident from the creator,
但它并没有被标注为历史
but it isn’t listed as history,
或者任何科目
or any subject for that matter.
紧挨着它的一个是英语的数学课
The one directly next to it is a math lesson in English.
它和历史没有任何关系
No part of this has history,
但它却出现在历史搜索里
but it’s here on the history search.
事实上 无论你输入什么科目 结果都完全一样
In fact, any subject that you put in will have the exact same results.
这些是英语的、与创业相关的所有课程
Here are all the lessons that are in English and relate to entrepreneurship,
还有计算机科学、电竞和地理
and computer science, and esports, and geography.
哦看 是希腊语的心脏解剖课 哇 真疯狂！
Oh look, it’s the heart dissection in Greek, wow, that’s crazy!
截至本视频发布时
As of posting this video,
它不再以完全相同的方式出错了
it doesn’t still work in this exact same way,
但它仍然不能正常工作
but it still does not work correctly.
所以我的观点依然成立
So my point still stands,
而且这部分已经开始变得冗长了
and this part’s already starting to drag on,
所以让我们继续吧
so let’s just move on.
这正是Gneiss Name两年前遇到的完全相同的问题
This is the exact same problem that Gneiss Name had literally two years ago.
这些课程数量很多
There are a lot of these lessons,
所以你们应该能搜索它们
so you should be able to fucking search them.
做一个真正能用的筛选功能有多难？
How hard is it to make an actual filter that fucking works,
这不可接受！
this is unacceptable!
这不可接受
This is unacceptable.
我想说清楚
I want to make it clear that
我要把责任明确归咎于微软
I am placing the blame specifically at the feet of Microsoft,
而不是制作这个版本的个人
not the individual people who make this version.
他们知道这些东西是坏的
They know that these things are broken,
因为他们有正常工作的眼睛
because they have functioning eyeballs,
但他们在该项目上的团队太小了 根本没有时间修复
but they are such a small team on this project that they don’t have time to fix them.
微软经常做这种事
Microsoft does this thing a lot,
买下一个东西 然后给一小队开发人员微薄的预算
where they buy a thing and then give a shoestring budget to a small team of developers
告诉他们自己想办法
and tell them to just deal with it.
这里发生的事显然就是如此
This is very clearly what is happening here.
别怪那些普通开发者
Don’t blame the individual devs.
怪微软
Blame Microsoft.
微软的生意之道就是尽可能少花钱
Microsoft is in the business of spending as little money as humanly possible
获取尽可能高的回报
to get the highest return possible.
你知道2026年做到这一点最好的方式是什么吗？
And you know the best way to do that in 2026?
是生成式AI
It’s generative AI.
“耶耶耶” 所有人说道
“Yayyy,” everyone said.
天哪 我们终于要在这个频道上聊生成式AI了
Oh god, we’re finally going to talk about generative AI on this channel.
我的天
Jesus Christ.
好 让我把话说清楚
Okay, let me be clear.
我讨厌AI生成的艺术
I hate AI-generated art.
我讨厌AI生成的文字
I hate AI-generated text.
我讨厌每次谷歌搜索顶部都有一个AI概览 就那样对你撒谎
And I hate that every Google search has an AI overview at the top that just lies to you.
我一直在往披萨里加胶水 每天至少吃一颗小石头
I’ve been putting glue in my pizza and eating at least one small rock per day,
我觉得这不太健康
and I don’t think it’s healthy.
我确实认为生成式AI在某些场景下是有用的
I do think that generative AI can be useful in some scenarios,
但它并不能真正节省时间 因为你总是需要一个合格的人来审核
but it doesn’t really save time because you always need a qualified human to look over it.
而且AI带来的好处 不值得用所有人电费上涨、破坏环境
And the benefits that AI provides are not worth everyone’s power bills going up,
以及把整个经济押在上面来换取
destroying the environment,
and staking the entire economy on.
好了 现在我们可以在有趣的教育版里聊聊AI了
Okay, cool. Now we can talk about AI in the funny Minecraft: Education Edition.
过去几年里
For the past couple years,
AI一直是这个超级流行的热词
AI has been this super popular buzzword.
所以 显然
So, obviously,
他们想在人们面前摇晃AI这把钥匙串 好说
they want to jingle the AI keys in front of them to say,
嘿 嘿 我们很时髦 我们也懂AI
hey, hey, we’re hip, we also know AI,
而且我们正在教学生们关于AI的一切
and we’re teaching students all about it.
有几节课宣称里面有AI
There are a couple lessons that mention that they have AI in them,
但别被骗了
but don’t be fooled.
它们里面实际上并没有像大语言模型那样生成答案的东西
These don’t actually have, like, a LLM in them that’s producing answers or anything.
它只是用经典的“AI一小时”积木教授AI基础
It’s teaching AI foundations with the classic Hour of AI blocks.
这和当年qCraft教孩子们量子力学的方式很像
It’s a lot like how qCraft was teaching kids about quantum mechanics.
想想吧
Think of that.
Minecraft教育版确实使用了真正的生成式AI
Minecraft Education does use real, genuine, generative AI,
但我没法访问它 因为它被锁在后面 只对真正的老师开放
but I couldn’t get access to it because it is locked in the back for real teachers only.
隆重介绍AI课程制作器
Introducing the AI Lesson Crafter.
它利用微软的Azure和OpenAI技术
It uses Microsoft’s Azure and OpenAI technology to
为老师生成基于Minecraft的自定义课程
generate custom Minecraft-based lessons for teachers.
当你只需向Chat要一节课时 谁还需要筛选功能呢
Who needs filtering to work when you can just ask Chat for a lesson,
每节课都自带一套说明和一份美国教育标准清单
each with their own set of instructions and a list of United States educational standards
说明通过这节课你能达到哪些标准
that you’re meeting by doing this lesson.
目前它只对真正的老师开放预览
It’s currently in preview for real teachers only,
但在这篇文章里 他们说它会在2025年对所有用户开放
but in this article they said it would be available to all users in 2025.
真让人震惊和意外
Shock and surprise,
现在是2026年 它还是没出
it’s 2026 and still not out.
GTA 6还是AI课程制作器
GTA 6 or AI Lesson Crafter,
请在评论区下注
place your bets in the comments.
说真的 这整个概念极其可怕
Seriously though, this whole concept is extremely scary.
一个修改版的ChatGPT有权替学生决定什么是真的
A modified ChatGPT gets to choose what is real for students,
尽管它已经被证明会胡编乱造、撒谎 并盲目附和用户
even though it has been shown to hallucinate and lie and blindly agree with the user.
如果它给出实际上并不存在的教育标准 而他们照做了呢？
What if it gives educational standards that aren’t actually real and they follow them?
如果信息本身就是错的呢？
What if the information itself is wrong?
我认为这真的至关重要
I think that it really deeply matters
我们社会的基础不该被AI
that the base of our society is not being misinformed by AI
被他们自己的老师
by their own teachers,
那些他们本该信任的人  误导
who they’re supposed to trust.
但我能理解他们为什么这么做
But I can see why they did this
因为在纸面上 它是MinecraftEdu问题的终极解决方案
because on paper it’s the ultimate solution to MinecraftEdu’s problems.
没有教育标准？
No educational standards?
AI可以帮你造出来
The AI can make them for you.
哦 制作世界太花时间？
Oh, the worlds take too long to make?
AI会尝试制作能让你的学生大展创造力的课程
The AI will try to make lessons that let your students’ creativity shine
让每节课都发生在一个适合建造的空白平坦世界上
by having each lesson take place on a blank, flat world that is perfect for building.
没有足够符合你想教内容的教案？
Not enough lesson plans for exactly what you want to teach?
AI可以生成你想要的任何教案
The AI can generate whatever lesson plan you want.
公平地说 每当Minecraft以任何方式提到AI时
To be fair, whenever Minecraft talks about AI in any capacity,
他们都会确保提醒你 使用前需要仔细核对
they make sure to say that you need to double-check it before you use it.
但我认为这有点像是在推卸责任 两头都想占
But I think that this is kind of a cop-out and trying to have it both ways.
你得知道人们不会检查两遍 对吧？
Like, you’ve got to know that people aren’t going to check it twice, right?
这就是AI可怕的地方
That’s the terrible thing with AI.
它会满怀自信地对你撒谎
It will just lie to you, with full confidence.
以难以察觉的方式撒谎
Lie in ways that are difficult to even notice,
慢慢把你认为的真相侵蚀成万物的平均值
slowly eroding what you thought was true into the average of everything.
而这一切中最糟糕的是
And the worst part of all of this is that
由于你无法购买教育版
since you cannot buy Minecraft: Education Edition,
他们可以随时、以任何理由拔掉整个产品的电源
they can just pull the plug on the whole thing at any time, for any reason.
而那些在过去10年里
And the teachers that have made payments
累计支付了1200美元的老师们
adding up to $1200 over the past 10 years
将没有游戏、没有课程 很可能也没有赔偿
will have no game, no lessons, and probably no compensation
因为这家伙靠削减预算为生
because this guy feeds off of budget cuts.
如果你想看一个典型的例子
If you want to see a prime example of this,
看看我们的老朋友TeacherGaming就够了
look no further than our old friend TeacherGaming.
2021年4月17日
On April 17th, 2021,
TeacherGaming网站从他们的商店页面
the TeacherGaming website was changed from their store page
变成了这样
to this.
游戏结束
Game over.
他们说道 引用原文
They said, quote,
“尽管我们竭尽全力
“Despite our best efforts,
我们仍未能让TG Desk应用取得商业成功
we weren’t able to turn the TG Desk app into a commercial success.
这就是为什么我们将在下个月终止剩余的服务
That’s why we’re pulling the plug on the remaining services next month.
在那之后 游戏下载、教案、数据分析、课堂
After that, game downloads, lesson plans, analytics, classes,
以及TeacherGaming应用和网站都将不再可用”
and the TeacherGaming app and websites will no longer be available.”
用户只有44天时间下载他们通过Teacher Gaming购买的所有游戏
Users had 44 days to download all of the games that they bought through Teacher Gaming,
之后它们就会被全部删除
and then they would all be deleted.
而这就是他们的全部生意
And that was their entire business.
请记住 对微软来说
Keep in mind that for Microsoft,
教育版只是他们庞大企业帝国中微不足道的一小部分
Education Edition is just a teeny tiny part of their huge conglomerate.
他们不在乎
They do not care.
我们在本视频中一次又一次地看到了这一点
We have seen this over and over again in this video.
那么 Minecraft教育版那无限的价格 值得吗？
So, is the infinite price of Minecraft Education worth it?
不值！！
NO!!
这显然是最烂、最不成熟的Minecraft当前版本
This is easily the worst, most underdeveloped current version of Minecraft.
而且它还是建立在本已糟糕、充满bug的基岩版之上
And it’s on top of the already terrible, buggy Bedrock Edition.
微软应该为这是自己公司的一部分而感到羞耻
Microsoft should be embarrassed that this is part of their company.
他们15年前制作MinecraftEdu时投入的时间和心血
The time and attention to detail they put into making MinecraftEdu 15 years ago now
如今已全部化为乌有
is all just gone.
我可以谈谈MinecraftEdu如何没有完全按计划进行之类
I can talk about how MinecraftEdu didn’t really go according to plan or whatever,
但这个真的是坏掉的
but this is literally broken.
到处都是问题
All over the place.
而且人们多年来一直在告诉他们它是坏的
And people have told them that it’s broken for years,
而他们什么都没做
and they haven’t done anything.
而作为一个号称教育性的产品
And as a supposedly educational product,
它连唯一的工作 提供真实信息 都做不到
it fails at its only job of providing true information.
在研究这个视频的过程中
While researching this video,
我真的很喜欢上了游戏化教育
I really came around to liking gaming in education.
它真的有效
It really does work,
而教育版本可以如此出色
and Minecraft: Education Edition could be so good.
它由一家资金雄厚的大公司打造
It’s created by a big company with tons of funding.
它本可以轻松超越MinecraftEdu
It could be better than MinecraftEdu easily.
正因如此 微软却只让整个项目苟延残喘 才如此可悲
Which is why it’s so sad that Microsoft just keeps this whole thing on life support instead.
我一直很难给这个视频想一个结尾
I’ve been having a really hard time trying to make an ending for this video.
很难是因为 实在没有什么让人感觉良好的方式来表述这件事
And it’s difficult because there isn’t really, like, a feel-good way to say this.
微软有两个选择
Microsoft has two options.
要么他们开始资助教育版
Either they can start funding Education Edition,
调更多人手过去
move more people over there,
并通过让它成为它本该成为的真正版本
and show that they actually care about education
来证明他们真的关心教育
by making this the true version that it was always meant to be.
或者……
Or…
他们可以继续什么都不做
they can just continue to do nothing,
让这个本来很好的版本烂在藤上吧
and let this perfectly good version rot on the vine.
而鉴于他们上个月刚解雇了4800名员工
And given that they just fired 4,800 workers last month,
你们大胆猜猜我觉得哪个更有可能
take a wild guess at which one I think is more likely.
晚安
Goodnight.
原标题：The History of Minecraft's Worst Version 原作者：DIMM4
原视频上传日期：2026年8月22日
翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
♡无偿翻译，用爱发电♡
有能力的请到Youtube上支持原作者
字幕制作不易，喜欢的话支持一下我吧！(*ﾟ∀ﾟ*)
（你以为结束了吗？）
让我用ChatGPT来问我人生中的每一件事
Let me ask ChatGPT about every single thing in my entire life.
他对那只羊做了什么！？
What is he doing to the sheep!?